urlprofiler.com 2019-02-05

# URL Profiler Privacy Notice - URL Profiler

This Privacy Notice is a public statement of how URL Profiler applies data protection principles to processing data. It will provide clarity on who is collecting the data, what data is being collected, and what is being done with the data.

## Who we are

URL Profiler is a product developed by Polychrome Ltd (Company Registration Number 09033768). The management of Polychrome Ltd is located at Hill View, Bell Lane, Biddenden, Kent TN27 8LD.

This Privacy Notice governs the collection, storage and use of personal information collected by Polychrome Ltd, via the website at urlprofiler.com, through the desktop software ‘URL Profiler,’ and any 3rd parties used by the organisation.

## What we collect

We ask for your name and email address when you signup to our service. This allows us to send you licenses via serial number, to enable you to use the software.

For licensing and security reasons we also collect your computer IP address, and your machine name.

We may additionally ask you for more information when you report a problem with the URL Profiler software, to enable us to help you in finding a solution.

## What we do with your personal data

The personal data we collect will be used for the following purpose:

  * To assign trial or paid licenses to you, which enables you to use the software.
  * To allow us to disambiguate users, so that we can offer every user a free trial license.
  * To prevent abuse of the free trial license, for instance a single user signing up with multiple different email addresses.
  * To send support messages to you, to help you to use the software successfully.
  * To send marketing emails to you (note that we only do this if you explicitly opt-in to marketing emails, a separate consent to accessing the software).

Our legal basis for processing personal data is as follows:

  * Contract – when you sign up for a URL Profiler trial or paid license, you are entering into a contract with URL Profiler, allowing us to grant you a license to use the software.
  * Legitimate Interests – it is in our business interest that we do not open ourselves to abuse of the free trial provision.

## How is the data stored?

Data is stored in our secure UK datacentre, and backed up regularly offline. This data has heavily restricted access, to authorised personnel only.

The list below details all the third parties we share your data with, and some of these are located outside the EU. However, all of these companies are GDPR compliant, and we have signed a Data Processing Addendum (DPA) which complies with GDPR.

## Who we share your personal data with

To help us deliver URL Profiler we use various third party applications and services, with which we share your personal data, in order to deliver a better service.

With each of these companies, we have already sought a Data Processing Addendum (DPA) which complies with GDPR. In most cases, we have already received and signed this DPA, and all remaining have ensured that we will have a DPA in place by 25th May.

These third parties are as follows:

  * [Customer.io](https://customer.io/), which is a messaging and support application. We use Customer.io to track usage of the URL Profiler software, and email messages to help you use the product more successfully. These messages include updates about the product’s development, highlight features, and deliver support content.
  * [Mandrill](https://mandrillapp.com/), which is an email delivery service. We use Mandrill to deliver emails necessary to setting up and managing your URL Profiler account (e.g. ‘Here is your serial number’).
  * [Groove](https://www.groovehq.com/), which is support helpdesk software. We use Groove to track and respond to users regarding issues or questions about the URL Profiler software. To assist us further in finding a solution, we may ask for additional information in certain circumstances, however providing this data is not mandatory.
  * [Raygun](https://raygun.com/), which is bug tracking software. We use Raygun to identify when users experience errors using the software, and to help us understand the errors more completely.
  * [FastSpring](https://fastspring.com/), which is payment and licensing software. We use FastSpring as our payment gateway, which allows users to sign up for one of URL Profiler’s paid subscription plans. FastSpring is effectively a reseller of the URL Profiler software, so you enter into a separate contract with them. We do not share any personal data with FastSpring, although we do have access to the personal data that they collect via a secure login, and via API, on our own secure servers.
  * [Xero](https://www.xero.com/), which is accounting and book-keeping software. We only use Xero in special cases, where users are unable to sign up via FastSpring, and require us to invoice them directly. In such cases, we collect and store a name, email address, company name and company address. This data is not shared with any other systems, and is only used for accounting purposes.
  * [G Suite](https://gsuite.google.com/), which is a set of productivity tools. We use G Suite as our email provider, so most email communications from the company is routed through G Suite.

## How will the information be used

Your personal data is primarily used in the process of creating and managing a user account. Licenses are assigned against a user account, which enables users to access and use the software. We do not collect or use any data unless a user signs up for an account in the first place.

Additionally, we also use the data for the following reasons:

  * To provide ‘onboarding’ support, in order to help users get set up correctly when initially using the software.
  * To provide ongoing support, to help users successfully use the software, and introduce them to new or unused features.
  * To help users when they get stuck or encounter problems using the software.
  * To track and resolve bugs and issues in the software.
  * To send marketing emails, both product-related and informational/educational content.

## How long will the data be stored for?

The data will be stored for the lifetime of the service. One of the primary reasons we collect and store personal data is so that we can offer every user a free trial of the software, without the significant business risk that this offer be abused by users registering multiple trials from different email addresses.

By matching email address data with computer and IP address data, we can mitigate this risk and prevent abuse, since we have a much more accurate idea of who has tried the software previously.

Since this could occur at any future point in time, it is necessary for us to store this data up until the point where the business is no longer trading.

## What rights do you have?

As the data subject, you have the following rights:

  * The right to ask us to provide you with copies of personal information held about you at any time, free of charge.
  * The right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal information held about you, free of charge.
  * The right to opt out of any marketing communications that we (or any third party to whom we have disclosed your personal information with your consent) may send you.
  * The right to have your personal information deleted and removed from our systems, and any 3rd parties whom we have shared your data with.

## What happens if I ask for my personal information to be deleted?

We will need to close your URL Profiler account, meaning you no longer have access to use the software. We will then remove all records of your personal data from our internal data stores, and go through the user deletion process for each of our third parties with whom your personal data may be shared. Please see the list above for the full details of third parties.

## What we don’t and won’t ever do

We don’t, and never will sell or rent your information to any third party.

## What happens to my data during and after the free trial?

When you sign up for the free trial with URL Profiler, you enter into a contract with us, for us to provide you with access to the software for the duration of the trial. During this period, and for a short time after, we will contact you in order to help you use the software successfully, and support you should you run into any issues. Once this period is over, we will not contact you again for any reason.

We will still however store your personal data, as we need this to help manage the free trial provision.

## Cookies

The urlprofiler.com website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the website. This helps us provide you with a good experience when you browse the website, and also allows us to improve the website.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that are stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

### The cookies we use

We make use of the following cookies:

  * **Necessary cookies.**  These are cookies that are required for the operation of the urlprofiler.com website.
  * **Statistics  cookies.** These cookies help us recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the website when they are using it. This helps us improve the way the website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

**Please note that we do not set any cookies or collect any data through cookies for marketing purposes.**

### Third party cookies

Please note that third parties (e.g. Google Analytics) also set cookies, over which we have limited control. These cookies are only used for analytical purposes, to help us understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting and reporting information anonymously. No personally identifiable data is sent to third parties via cookies.

The following third parties set cookies on the URL Profiler website:

  * **Google Analytics**  – this is a product that tracks user behaviour across the website. Google Analytics set some cookies to allow them to follow user paths and identify unique users. We have set up our Google Analytics code so that it does not set or store a UserID, and so that it anonymizes IP addresses. As such, no personally identifiable information is stored.
  * **Typekit**  – this is an Adobe product that provides web fonts which we use on the website. Typekit set a cookie in order to collect information about the fonts being served to each site. This data does not include any information about the users who are visiting the website ([read more here](https://blog.typekit.com/2013/06/13/clarifying-our-commitment-to-privacy/)).
  * **YouTube** – this is a video hosting platform, and we have some YouTube videos embedded on the site. YouTube set some cookies help them track the number of views for a particular video. One of the cookies they set tracks user preferences to serve up related content or adverts within an embedded YouTube video.
  * **Wistia** – this is a video hosting platform, and we have some Wistia videos embedded on the site. Wistia set some cookies help them track the number of views for a particular video.

### Further information about cookies

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the urlprofiler.com website. If you would like more information from an independent resource on a range of cookie-related issues, including how to change your browser settings, please visit [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## How can you raise a complaint?

If you wish to exercise any of your rights as stated above, make a data access request, have a question about our Privacy Notice, or wish to raise a complaint, please do not hesitate to contact Patrick Hathaway (Polychrome Ltd Director) on [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
